# Michelle Tran

# **Full Stack Web Developer**

Pennsauken, NJ | +1-856-313-8545 | tranmichelle997@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/m-chelletran | Github: aithub.com/michelletrn | Portfolio: michelletrn.aithub.io/react-portolio/

#### SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with a nursing background and a passion for building user-friendly applications. Successfully obtained a certificate from Rutgers University for Full Stack Development. Possess a solid foundation of valuable soft skills acquired through nursing experience that are applicable to development, including emotional intelligence. With a focus on continuous learning and demonstrated critical thinking and collaboration skills, this individual seeks a position as a full stack developer.

#### SKILLS

- Front-end HTML | CSS | JavaScript | JQuery | React.Js | Bootstrap | Materialize
- Back-end MySQL/Sequelize | MongoDB/Apollo/GraphQL | API Design | Node.Js
- Developer Tools Heroku | Git | Github Pages | Testing

## **EDUCATION**

## **Full Stack Flex Program (Certificate)**

November 2022 - February 2023

Rutgers University Coding Boot Camp

Obtained skills to build web applications from end-to-end using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

## **Bachelor of Science**

September 2016 – May 2020

**Rutgers University** 

Major in Nursing | Cum Laude | GPA 3.6

PROJECTS/INVOLVEMENTS (github.com/michelletrn)

Personal Portfolio | App: https://michelletrn.github.io/react-portfolio/ | Repo: https://github.com/michelletrn/react-portfolio

• Javascript personal portfolio website using React to conditionally render components.

Recipefinder | App: https://k-meal-planner.herokuapp.com/ | Repo: https://github.com/michelletrn/k-meal-planner

- MERN stack application built using JSON Web Token for user authentication, Stripe for payment, and other technologies (Bootstrap/custom CSS, API, GQL)
- Users can search and save recipes, add recipe ingredients to a shopping cart or email a shopping list to themselves.

Self Journal Post | App: https://self-journal-post.herokuapp.com/ | Repo: https://github.com/jennahopeclem/self-journal

- Contributed to team's backend development, created a journal posting application that requires user authentication where users can post entries and comment on other user entries, application deployed to Heroku.
- Javascript application built using: Node, Express, API (location, news articles), Materialize, MySQL/Sequelize, Handlebars, Github for version control.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## Registered Nurse (Nov 2020 - Oct 2022)

Virtua Home Care | Mt Laurel, NJ

May 2022 - October 2022

- Provided quality and passionate care to 6 patients daily in the home environment.
- Managed a case-load of 25 patients, organized subsequent visits based on patient needs while working in coordination with other health care professionals to articulate patient requirements and changes in health status.
- Optimized **time management** and **prioritization**, while adapting to dynamic work conditions beyond the traditional work setting.
- Organized and involved patients in the plan of care while prioritizing high risk patients and quality of care in mind.

Cooper University Hospital | Camden, NJ

March 2021 - March 2022

- Application and implementation of nursing ethics and methodologies to deliver passionate and quality patient care.
- Utilized a wide range of medical equipment, demonstrating expertise in operating procedures and **interpreting** patient data.
- Displayed leadership as Charge Nurse, overseeing a team of 9 10 clinical staff members within a 12 hour night shift.
- **Innovated** by researching and introducing a cost-saving project that enhances staff performance and patient outcomes, the project was presented to nursing colleagues and administrators.
- Demonstrated exceptional **collaboration** skills, working within a **multidisciplinary team** to evaluate, monitor, and provide care to patients in a dynamic environment.
- Proven ability to navigate and adapt to shifting environments and responsibilities.